<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:3000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-07T22:50:21+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">The Future of Web Design Powered by AI</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2023/12/30/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Web Design Powered by AI" /><published>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2023/12/30/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2023/12/30/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2023-12-30-blog-cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size " style="text-align: center;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>The Future of Web Design Powered by AI</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size " style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>The Future of Web Design Powered by AI</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size ">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
          <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        30 December 2023
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/pebojote" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            03/29/2021
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/pebojote" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
<p>
 Crafting a website that people love to use involves more than just making it look good. It's like building a house – you start with a plan (sitemap) and a basic structure (wireframes) before adding the details. Ever heard of skeuomorphism? It's about making things on your site look familiar, like real-world objects, which can make users feel more comfortable.
</p>
<p>
  Now, imagine your website as a tour guide. It should help users explore without getting lost. Simple, right? And when it comes to naming things, clarity is key. If users can't understand what a button does, you've got a problem.
</p>
<p>
  Conway's Law suggests that how a company is organized influences how a website is designed. So, teamwork is crucial. And speaking of teamwork, a good website is like a well-organized library – your data (books) needs a clear structure (shelves) for users to find what they need easily.
</p>
</div>

<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
<p>
  Assumptions are a tricky thing. Different designs come with different assumptions, and the only way to know if they work is to test them with real users. It's a bit like being a mind reader – you need to understand what users want and expect.
</p>
<p>
 And then, there's psychology. Web designers need to think like psychologists, understanding how users think and behave. Leading questions won't get you far – you need to ask open-ended ones to really understand what users are thinking
</p>
<p>
  Prototyping is like a rough sketch before the final masterpiece. It helps designers visualize ideas and get feedback early on. And paper mockups are like the doodles on the margins – quick, low-cost ways to brainstorm.
</p>
</div>

<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
<p>
  Testing is essential. A/B testing compares different versions of a webpage to see which one users prefer. Guerrilla testing is like catching users off guard, getting their real, unfiltered feedback.
</p>
</div>

<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
<p>
The principle of least surprise is about making your website behave in ways users expect, minimizing confusion. Non-functional requirements, like security and accessibility, are the unsung heroes – you only notice them when they're not there.
</p>
<p>
Keeping a "designer book" is like having a diary for your creative thoughts and lessons learned. Consistency is good, but a little intentional inconsistency can grab attention. Fidelity is about how detailed your design is – it depends on where you are in the process.
</p>
<p>
Spacing matters. Padding and margin are like the breathing room in your design. Effective communication between designers and developers is like speaking the same language – it ensures a smooth translation from design to reality.
</p>
</div>

<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
<p>
Okay, let's break down how adding artificial intelligence (AI) to web design can really step up the game:
</p>
<p>
1. <b>Tailoring Experiences with Smart AI:</b>
   - Imagine AI algorithms as your personal assistants. They study how users behave, what they like, and their past interactions to customize the website just for them. It's like having a tailor-made experience for each visitor.
</p>

<p>
2. <b>Your Website's Intelligent Tour Guide:</b>
   - Ever wished your website could guide users like a helpful tour guide? AI-driven chatbots or virtual assistants do just that. They smoothly assist users in navigating the site, answering questions in real-time, and even suggesting personalized recommendations.

</p>

<p>
3. <b>Making Names User-Friendly with AI:</b>
   - Naming buttons and navigation elements can be tricky, but AI, through Natural Language Processing, helps optimize these names. By analyzing user feedback, it suggests clear and user-friendly labels, making everything more understandable.

</p>

<p>
4. <b>Streamlining Teamwork with AI:</b>
   - AI tools analyze how your team is structured and how they work together. This insight optimizes collaboration and communication, following Conway's Law to make the design process more efficient.

</p>

<p>
5. <b>Testing Assumptions the User-Centric Way:</b>
   - AI, powered by machine learning, digs into user data to confirm or challenge design assumptions. It's like having a crystal ball that predicts user preferences and behaviors, helping designers make decisions based on real insights.

</p>

<p>
6. <b>Understanding Users through AI Psychology:</b>
   - AI dives into massive datasets to give designers a peek into user psychology. This means creating interfaces that really resonate with the audience, all thanks to AI's analysis of user behavior.

</p>

<p>
7. <b>AI Jazzing Up Prototyping and Mockups:</b>
   - AI-powered design tools take the weight off designers by automating parts of prototyping. They generate interactive prototypes based on user input and feedback, even offering design suggestions for those initial paper mockups.

</p>

<p>
8. <b>Swift AI Testing for Optimal Design:</b>
   - AI-driven testing tools automate the A/B testing process, rapidly sifting through user responses to different designs. It's like having a super-speedy assistant analyzing user feedback, giving detailed insights for design improvements.

</p>

<p>
9. <b>Predicting User Expectations with AI:</b>
   - AI's predictive modeling anticipates what users expect. This helps designers align with the principle of least surprise, ensuring a more intuitive and user-friendly interface.

</p>

<p>
10. <b>AI Boosting Security and Accessibility:</b>
    - AI takes on a superhero role by enhancing security. It analyzes potential threats in real-time and even helps maintain accessibility standards throughout the design journey.

</p>

<p>
11. <b>Automating Design Diaries with AI:</b>
    - Natural Language Processing in AI automates the documentation process. It extracts key insights and lessons from the design journey, maintaining a smart "designer book."

</p>

<p>
12. <b>Ensuring Consistency with AI:</b>
    - AI tools perform automated consistency checks, making sure all design elements across the website stick to predefined standards and guidelines.

</p>

<p>
13. <b>Enhancing User Experience with AI on Different Devices:</b>
    - AI, with its machine learning magic, studies how users behave on various devices. This helps suggest responsive design tweaks, making sure the user experience is top-notch, no matter the gadget.

</p>
<p>
So, by teaming up with AI in web design, it's like having a brilliant assistant that adds data-driven insights, automation, and predictions into the creative mix. AI becomes your partner, boosting human creativity with smart automation and well-informed decision-making.

</p>
</div>

<div style="text-align: left;font-family:sans-serif;">
<h3>Summary</h3>
</div>
<hr />
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
<p>
In the end, it's about creating a website that adapts to different devices (responsive design) and offers a consistent, enjoyable experience. Web design is an ever-evolving journey, and by embracing user testing, good communication, and continuous learning, designers can make it a successful one.
</p>
</div>

<hr />

<div class="desktop__size ">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/03/29/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    &nbsp;
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/03/29/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Embark on the journey of crafting a user-centric website with a holistic approach to web design. From foundational elements like sitemaps and wireframes to the nuances of psychological insights, this exploration covers essential principles and methodologies.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bikepacking/Trek</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2023/12/01/biking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bikepacking/Trek" /><published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2023/12/01/biking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2023/12/01/biking/"><![CDATA[<div class="container p-0">
  <div class="row p-0">
    
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
          <video class="embed-responsive-item w-100" controls="">
            <source src="/assets/videos/202401-07-0_2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
            Your browser does not support the video tag.
          </video>
        </div>
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">8.9 km Adventures: Navigating Life's Hurdles</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample1">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading1">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse1" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse1">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse1" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading1" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample1">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">So, check this out—I spill the beans about my life's hurdles, right? I cover a whopping 8.9 km of ground. Now, I'm not totally sold on Google Maps being the distance guru, but trust me, it feels like a marathon, especially with all those steep climbs. Oh, and get this—I hit a hydration low on the journey, so what's a gal to do? I channel my inner survivalist and take a swig from a spring. LOL! Life's an adventure!</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">So, check this out—I spill the beans about my life's hurdles, right? I cover a whopping 8.9 km of ground. Now, I'm not totally sold on Google Maps being the distance guru, but trust me, it feels like a marathon, especially with all those steep climbs.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%218876&amp;authkey=%21ACKEZKDwonPYXKc" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 4" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Journey’s Pause</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample2">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading2">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse2" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse2">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse2" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading2" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample2">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Just took a breather from a thrilling ride up the hills. Parked my bike against this wooden railing, and boy, what a view! Mountains meeting the sea, under a clear sky - nature at its best. Felt like I was on top of the world. Can’t wait to hit the trail again!</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Just took a breather from a thrilling ride up the hills. Parked my bike against this wooden railing, and boy, what a view! Mountains meeting the sea, under a clear sky - nature at its best.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2115330&amp;authkey=%21ADC17Lt-6CWs-0A" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 3" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Riding with the Waves</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample3">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading3">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse3" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse3">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse3" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading3" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample3">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Just had an amazing day riding along this beautiful coastline. The sound of the waves crashing and the sea breeze made it all the more refreshing. My trusty bike, equipped with my essentials, was my companion on this journey. The greenery meeting the beach was a sight to behold. It was a day well spent, embracing the harmony of nature and adventure. Can’t wait for more rides like this!</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Just had an amazing day riding along this beautiful coastline. The sound of the waves crashing and the sea breeze made it all the more refreshing. My trusty bike, equipped with my essentials, was my companion on this journey.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2115332&amp;authkey=%21ACUgGnNDIhyv0HU" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 2" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Muddy Trails and Gears</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample4">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading4">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse4" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse4">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse4" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading4" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample4">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Just got back from an epic ride! The trails were muddy, but that didn’t stop me. My bike’s gears are caked in mud - a sign of a day well spent. Can’t wait to clean her up and get back out there!</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Just got back from an epic ride! The trails were muddy, but that didn’t stop me. My bike’s gears are caked in mud - a sign of a day well spent. Can’t wait to clean her up and get back out there!</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2115333&amp;authkey=%21AK4bk_1m_Nn-ZEk" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 1" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Journey’s Pause: Embracing the Sea</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample5">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading5">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse5" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse5">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse5" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading5" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample5">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">There I was, taking a breather from my cycling journey. The sea was my companion, its waves rhythmically crashing onto the shore. My bike, laden with bags, stood as a testament to the miles traveled and the adventures experienced. The clear sky overhead seemed to echo my sense of freedom. This wasn’t just a ride, it was a story unfolding with each pedal stroke.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">There I was, taking a breather from my cycling journey. The sea was my companion, its waves rhythmically crashing onto the shore. My bike, laden with bags, stood as a testament to the miles traveled and the adventures experienced.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
  </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your browser does not support the video tag. 8.9 km Adventures: Navigating Life's Hurdles Description So, check this out—I spill the beans about my life's hurdles, right? I cover a whopping 8.9 km of ground. Now, I'm not totally sold on Google Maps being the distance guru, but trust me, it feels like a marathon, especially with all those steep climbs. Oh, and get this—I hit a hydration low on the journey, so what's a gal to do? I channel my inner survivalist and take a swig from a spring. LOL! Life's an adventure! So, check this out—I spill the beans about my life's hurdles, right? I cover a whopping 8.9 km of ground. Now, I'm not totally sold on Google Maps being the distance guru, but trust me, it feels like a marathon, especially with all those steep climbs. Journey’s Pause Description Just took a breather from a thrilling ride up the hills. Parked my bike against this wooden railing, and boy, what a view! Mountains meeting the sea, under a clear sky - nature at its best. Felt like I was on top of the world. Can’t wait to hit the trail again! Just took a breather from a thrilling ride up the hills. Parked my bike against this wooden railing, and boy, what a view! Mountains meeting the sea, under a clear sky - nature at its best. Riding with the Waves Description Just had an amazing day riding along this beautiful coastline. The sound of the waves crashing and the sea breeze made it all the more refreshing. My trusty bike, equipped with my essentials, was my companion on this journey. The greenery meeting the beach was a sight to behold. It was a day well spent, embracing the harmony of nature and adventure. Can’t wait for more rides like this! Just had an amazing day riding along this beautiful coastline. The sound of the waves crashing and the sea breeze made it all the more refreshing. My trusty bike, equipped with my essentials, was my companion on this journey. Muddy Trails and Gears Description Just got back from an epic ride! The trails were muddy, but that didn’t stop me. My bike’s gears are caked in mud - a sign of a day well spent. Can’t wait to clean her up and get back out there! Just got back from an epic ride! The trails were muddy, but that didn’t stop me. My bike’s gears are caked in mud - a sign of a day well spent. Can’t wait to clean her up and get back out there! Journey’s Pause: Embracing the Sea Description There I was, taking a breather from my cycling journey. The sea was my companion, its waves rhythmically crashing onto the shore. My bike, laden with bags, stood as a testament to the miles traveled and the adventures experienced. The clear sky overhead seemed to echo my sense of freedom. This wasn’t just a ride, it was a story unfolding with each pedal stroke. There I was, taking a breather from my cycling journey. The sea was my companion, its waves rhythmically crashing onto the shore. My bike, laden with bags, stood as a testament to the miles traveled and the adventures experienced.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rock/Stone Climbing</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2023/08/01/climbing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rock/Stone Climbing" /><published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2023/08/01/climbing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2023/08/01/climbing/"><![CDATA[<div class="container p-0">
  <div class="row p-0">
    
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2115356&amp;authkey=%21AIfE_UluOLzMP_c" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 6" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Embracing the Wilderness: A Journey Unforgotten</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample1">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading1">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse1" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse1">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse1" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading1" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample1">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Today, I found myself lost in the best way possible. Along with my fellow adventurers, we ventured into the heart of an untouched forest, our backpacks filled with excitement and curiosity. The trail, a narrow path less trodden, led us through a maze of greenery, each turn revealing a new facet of nature’s grandeur. The air was thick with the scent of damp earth and blooming flora, a testament to the recent rain.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Today, I found myself lost in the best way possible. Along with my fellow adventurers, we ventured into the heart of an untouched forest, our backpacks filled with excitement and curiosity.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2115357&amp;authkey=%21AE-KrWAt6nQ1fRk" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 5" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">My Rock Climbing Adventure</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample2">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading2">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse2" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse2">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse2" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading2" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample2">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size"> Surrounded by our gear, my companion and I prepared ourselves for the ascent. The dirt beneath us, the vegetation around, and the massive rock face in front of us - it was a dance between us and nature. This experience was more than just a physical challenge; it was a testament to human will and perseverance. Truly an adventure to remember! 🧗‍♂️</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Surrounded by our gear, my companion and I prepared ourselves for the ascent. The dirt beneath us, the vegetation around, and the massive rock face in front of us - it was a dance between us and nature.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
          <video class="embed-responsive-item w-100" controls="">
            <source src="/assets/videos/Stone-Climb-August.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
            Your browser does not support the video tag.
          </video>
        </div>
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Scaling the Heights of Mountain</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample3">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading3">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse3" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse3">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse3" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading3" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample3">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">I had an amazing time stone climbing last August 2023. The views were breathtaking, the rocks were challenging, and the adrenaline was pumping. Check out this video of me reaching the top of one of the cliffs. It was a rewarding experience that I will never forget.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">I had an amazing time stone climbing last August 2023. The views were breathtaking, the rocks were challenging, and the adrenaline was pumping.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2110675&amp;authkey=%21ACon9oGOWXfLZHM" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 4" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Embracing the Misty Peaks</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample4">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading4">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse4" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse4">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse4" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading4" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample4">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Dressed in casual hiking attire, you all stand triumphantly on the grassy terrain, surrounded by the ethereal beauty of nature. The camaraderie among you is palpable, as you share this moment of victory and awe. The misty atmosphere adds a layer of mystery and excitement to your adventure, making this a truly memorable experience. This image beautifully encapsulates the essence of your journey - a testament to human resilience and the joy of exploration.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Dressed in casual hiking attire, you all stand triumphantly on the grassy terrain, surrounded by the ethereal beauty of nature. The camaraderie among you is palpable, as you share this moment of victory and awe.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2110689&amp;authkey=%21APcJ7xGCPqvy7_Q" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 3" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Rush and tranquility</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample5">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading5">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse5" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse5">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse5" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading5" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample5">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">The texture of the rock offers natural handholds and footholds, making the climb challenging yet achievable. A rope to my right ensures my safety during this adventurous ascent. The experience is a blend of adrenaline rush and tranquility, as I scale nature’s monolith, with the rustling leaves and the cool touch of the stone as my companions. This moment encapsulates the thrill of adventure and the beauty of nature, intertwined in a single frame.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">The texture of the rock offers natural handholds and footholds, making the climb challenging yet achievable. A rope to my right ensures my safety during this adventurous ascent.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2110708&amp;authkey=%21AEb8ry2UX_dkukI" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 2" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Scaling New Heights</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample6">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading6">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse6" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse6">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse6" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading6" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample6">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">In this captivating image, you are seen defying gravity, conquering the rugged cliff with sheer determination and skill. With safety gear in place and the vast sky as the backdrop, every grip and foothold marks a step closer to the summit. It’s a dance between human spirit and nature’s grandeur. The moment encapsulates the thrill of adventure, the joy of achievement, and the satisfaction of pushing personal boundaries.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">In this captivating image, you are seen defying gravity, conquering the rugged cliff with sheer determination and skill. With safety gear in place and the vast sky as the backdrop, every grip and foothold marks a step closer to the summit.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%2110704&amp;authkey=%21AP0lkTDl0ggqqaA" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 1" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Scaling the Heights of Adventure</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample7">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading7">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse7" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse7">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse7" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading7" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample7">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">The view from the top was breathtaking and rewarding. I felt a sense of accomplishment and gratitude for being able to enjoy the beauty of nature. Stone climbing is not for the faint of heart, but it is definitely worth trying at least once in your life. You never know what you might discover about yourself and the world around you.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">It was an exhilarating and challenging experience that tested my physical and mental limits.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
  </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Embracing the Wilderness: A Journey Unforgotten Description Today, I found myself lost in the best way possible. Along with my fellow adventurers, we ventured into the heart of an untouched forest, our backpacks filled with excitement and curiosity. The trail, a narrow path less trodden, led us through a maze of greenery, each turn revealing a new facet of nature’s grandeur. The air was thick with the scent of damp earth and blooming flora, a testament to the recent rain. Today, I found myself lost in the best way possible. Along with my fellow adventurers, we ventured into the heart of an untouched forest, our backpacks filled with excitement and curiosity. My Rock Climbing Adventure Description Surrounded by our gear, my companion and I prepared ourselves for the ascent. The dirt beneath us, the vegetation around, and the massive rock face in front of us - it was a dance between us and nature. This experience was more than just a physical challenge; it was a testament to human will and perseverance. Truly an adventure to remember! 🧗‍♂️ Surrounded by our gear, my companion and I prepared ourselves for the ascent. The dirt beneath us, the vegetation around, and the massive rock face in front of us - it was a dance between us and nature. Your browser does not support the video tag. Scaling the Heights of Mountain Description I had an amazing time stone climbing last August 2023. The views were breathtaking, the rocks were challenging, and the adrenaline was pumping. Check out this video of me reaching the top of one of the cliffs. It was a rewarding experience that I will never forget. I had an amazing time stone climbing last August 2023. The views were breathtaking, the rocks were challenging, and the adrenaline was pumping. Embracing the Misty Peaks Description Dressed in casual hiking attire, you all stand triumphantly on the grassy terrain, surrounded by the ethereal beauty of nature. The camaraderie among you is palpable, as you share this moment of victory and awe. The misty atmosphere adds a layer of mystery and excitement to your adventure, making this a truly memorable experience. This image beautifully encapsulates the essence of your journey - a testament to human resilience and the joy of exploration. Dressed in casual hiking attire, you all stand triumphantly on the grassy terrain, surrounded by the ethereal beauty of nature. The camaraderie among you is palpable, as you share this moment of victory and awe. Rush and tranquility Description The texture of the rock offers natural handholds and footholds, making the climb challenging yet achievable. A rope to my right ensures my safety during this adventurous ascent. The experience is a blend of adrenaline rush and tranquility, as I scale nature’s monolith, with the rustling leaves and the cool touch of the stone as my companions. This moment encapsulates the thrill of adventure and the beauty of nature, intertwined in a single frame. The texture of the rock offers natural handholds and footholds, making the climb challenging yet achievable. A rope to my right ensures my safety during this adventurous ascent. Scaling New Heights Description In this captivating image, you are seen defying gravity, conquering the rugged cliff with sheer determination and skill. With safety gear in place and the vast sky as the backdrop, every grip and foothold marks a step closer to the summit. It’s a dance between human spirit and nature’s grandeur. The moment encapsulates the thrill of adventure, the joy of achievement, and the satisfaction of pushing personal boundaries. In this captivating image, you are seen defying gravity, conquering the rugged cliff with sheer determination and skill. With safety gear in place and the vast sky as the backdrop, every grip and foothold marks a step closer to the summit. Scaling the Heights of Adventure Description The view from the top was breathtaking and rewarding. I felt a sense of accomplishment and gratitude for being able to enjoy the beauty of nature. Stone climbing is not for the faint of heart, but it is definitely worth trying at least once in your life. You never know what you might discover about yourself and the world around you. It was an exhilarating and challenging experience that tested my physical and mental limits.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Architecture for System Map Control</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2023/05/07/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Architecture for System Map Control" /><published>2023-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2023/05/07/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2023/05/07/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2023.05.07.blog.cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size " style="text-align: center;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Data Architecture for System Map Control</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size " style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Data Architecture for System Map Control</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size ">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
          <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        07 May 2023
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/pebojote" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            07 May 2023
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/pebojote" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <p>When designing a system, you must know what information you need to put on each component. The same thing applies when creating a table in the database. What information that table is holding and when searching for information schema, it is easier to navigate if you have enough rules for naming convention, because in large databases, you are more likely to take hours searching for the information you need to find when, in fact, if you know enough naming convention, it becomes easier.</p>
    <p>The same faith applies even to you as a person searching the internet. I know a lot of us take time to find the information we need. That’s why Google has made Google Scholar easier for researchers to find relevant information. This made it even easier by making an artificial intelligence called Chat GPT connect information together into a single page instead of navigating between pages.</p>
    <p>The function of these AIs is to create or generate text; they lack functionality such as deleting or even editing it. Every system component has unique functionality, and this functionality can be put into a single or separate component in a system. Each of these components has an attribute of information that is connected to the rest and makes the overall system identifiable.</p>
    <p>To make a map of these components, they made a mapping system called a map frame.</p>
    <p>For us human beings, we use tools such as a hammer to construct a house. For communication, we use the telephone. But as time passes, these tools become more and more digital, and we even integrate a paper plane to send new messages and propagate the energy needed to transfer the force of making something move. The architecture of these tools varies depending on the architecture of the data. Most often, the architecture of data is based on business needs. This is much easier data management for businesses, and it reduces the cost of operation. And to avoid risk.</p>
    <p>If the architecture of data is based on business needs, then the tools will, of course, focus on business needs, negating the needs of users. Business often gives us tools we don’t even need, negating the value of the product. It’s like forcing us to use a pen instead of a pickaxe to mine a stone. These business practises are often seen as good for businesses but bad for users. To do something is often the business's decision.</p>
    <p>The map frame of these tools becomes unusable, and the information we dig up becomes useless. To make the information useful, the tool should be useful. To make these tools useful for everyone, map them on the system based on the user’s needs.</p>
    <p>Do we put the right tools in the right room? In your home, you don’t put a hammer in your kitchen to cook. These still depend on the situation; if the business values security, then these tools will be put in different places. These tools will be valuable in some situations.</p>
    <h3>Summary</h3>
    <hr />
    <p>When designing a system, it is important to have enough rules for naming conventions to make it easier to navigate. Google has made Google Scholar and Chat GPT to make it easier for researchers to find relevant information. Each component in a system has unique functionality, which can be put into a single or separate component. A map frame is a system used to make a map of components such as a house, telephone, and paper plane. The architecture of these tools varies depending on the architecture of data, which is often based on business needs.</p>
    <p>To make the information useful, the tool should be useful and should be mapped on the system based on user's needs. To make the tools useful for everyone, it is important to map them on the system based on user's needs.</p>
</div>
<hr />
<div class="desktop__size ">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2023/05/07/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    &nbsp;
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2023/05/07/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my last article, I talked about distributed algorithms, but I like to talk about something relevant to us. Something that happened on Twitter recently and how it affected its users. Is it positive or negative? That depends on the scale of the emergency for the business.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Backpacking/Hiking/Camping</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2022/05/01/hiking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Backpacking/Hiking/Camping" /><published>2022-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2022/05/01/hiking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2022/05/01/hiking/"><![CDATA[<div class="container p-0">
  <div class="row p-0">
    
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
          <video class="embed-responsive-item w-100" controls="">
            <source src="/assets/videos/Mt. Pinginan.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
            Your browser does not support the video tag.
          </video>
        </div>
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Embracing the Horizon</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample1">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading1">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse1" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse1">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse1" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading1" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample1">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">As I stand on the peak of this verdant mountain, the world unfolds before me in a panorama of breathtaking beauty. Dressed in khaki, with my trusty orange and black backpack, I am a solitary figure against the vastness of nature. In my hands, I hold an object, a silent testament to my journey. Below me, the landscape is a tapestry of lush green, a testament to nature’s grandeur.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">As I stand on the peak of this verdant mountain, the world unfolds before me in a panorama of breathtaking beauty. Dressed in khaki, with my trusty orange and black backpack, I am a solitary figure against the vastness of nature.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%217832&amp;authkey=%21ANfF2RckoipmY38" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 4" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">The Changing Seasons</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample2">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading2">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse2" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse2">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse2" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading2" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample2">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Look at that hillside, isn’t it mesmerizing? You can see the dance between two seasons. The lush greenery is giving way to the rustic charm of autumn. It’s like nature is painting a masterpiece right before our eyes. Let’s take a moment to appreciate this beautiful transition. It’s not every day we get to witness such a spectacle.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Look at that hillside, isn’t it mesmerizing? You can see the dance between two seasons. The lush greenery is giving way to the rustic charm of autumn.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%217883&amp;authkey=%21AONtcUAH4uc9sFM" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 3" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">A Moment of Rest Amidst Nature</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample3">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading3">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse3" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse3">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse3" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading3" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample3">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Hey, isn’t this just the perfect spot to take a break? Surrounded by the whispering pines and the soft rustle of leaves, we find solace and a moment to breathe. The journey has been long, but look at the view – it’s all worth it! Let’s enjoy our snacks and recharge before we continue our adventure.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Hey, isn’t this just the perfect spot to take a break? Surrounded by the whispering pines and the soft rustle of leaves, we find solace and a moment to breathe.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%217838&amp;authkey=%21ANRlrvDPy_9TzSc" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 2" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Journey Through the Green Wilderness</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample4">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading4">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse4" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse4">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse4" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading4" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample4">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Look at us, guys! We’re surrounded by an abundance of greenery as we tread this hidden trail. The air is so fresh, and every step we take brings us deeper into the serene embrace of nature. Can you hear that? The rustling leaves and distant calls of wildlife. It’s as if the forest is sharing its secrets with us. Let’s keep going and see what other wonders this trail has in store for us.</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Look at us, guys! We’re surrounded by an abundance of greenery as we tread this hidden trail. The air is so fresh, and every step we take brings us deeper into the serene embrace of nature.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="col-md-4 mt-3 col-lg-3 p-0">
      <div class="card">
        
        <img src="https://onedrive.live.com/embed?resid=655EB2CF553A75A2%217861&amp;authkey=%21AHXT-pJfSAFMIr0" class="card-img-top" alt="Image 1" />
        
        <span class="mobile__size">
          <div class="card-body">
            <h5 class="card-title fw-lighter">Embracing the Horizon</h5>
            <div class="accordion" id="accordionExample5">
              <div class="accordion-item">
                <h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading5">
                  <button class="accordion-button block" type="button" data-bs-toggle="collapse" data-bs-target="#collapse5" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse5">
                    Description
                  </button>
                </h2>
                <div id="collapse5" class="accordion-collapse collapse block" aria-labelledby="heading5" data-bs-parent="#accordionExample5">
                  <div class="accordion-body">
                    <p class="card-text fw-lighter">
                      <span class="desktop__size">Wow, look at this, guys! We’ve made it to the top, and just take in that view – endless rolling green hills under a sky so vast, it’s breathtaking. Every step of our climb was worth this moment. It feels like we can touch the sky! Let’s take a moment to appreciate this, to breathe in the fresh air, and to realize how far we’ve come. This is what adventure feels like, isn’t it?</span>
                      <span class="mobile__size">Wow, look at this, guys! We’ve made it to the top, and just take in that view – endless rolling green hills under a sky so vast, it’s breathtaking. Every step of our climb was worth this moment.</span>
                    </p>
                  </div>
                </div>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </span>
      </div>
    </div>
    
  </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your browser does not support the video tag. Embracing the Horizon Description As I stand on the peak of this verdant mountain, the world unfolds before me in a panorama of breathtaking beauty. Dressed in khaki, with my trusty orange and black backpack, I am a solitary figure against the vastness of nature. In my hands, I hold an object, a silent testament to my journey. Below me, the landscape is a tapestry of lush green, a testament to nature’s grandeur. As I stand on the peak of this verdant mountain, the world unfolds before me in a panorama of breathtaking beauty. Dressed in khaki, with my trusty orange and black backpack, I am a solitary figure against the vastness of nature. The Changing Seasons Description Look at that hillside, isn’t it mesmerizing? You can see the dance between two seasons. The lush greenery is giving way to the rustic charm of autumn. It’s like nature is painting a masterpiece right before our eyes. Let’s take a moment to appreciate this beautiful transition. It’s not every day we get to witness such a spectacle. Look at that hillside, isn’t it mesmerizing? You can see the dance between two seasons. The lush greenery is giving way to the rustic charm of autumn. A Moment of Rest Amidst Nature Description Hey, isn’t this just the perfect spot to take a break? Surrounded by the whispering pines and the soft rustle of leaves, we find solace and a moment to breathe. The journey has been long, but look at the view – it’s all worth it! Let’s enjoy our snacks and recharge before we continue our adventure. Hey, isn’t this just the perfect spot to take a break? Surrounded by the whispering pines and the soft rustle of leaves, we find solace and a moment to breathe. Journey Through the Green Wilderness Description Look at us, guys! We’re surrounded by an abundance of greenery as we tread this hidden trail. The air is so fresh, and every step we take brings us deeper into the serene embrace of nature. Can you hear that? The rustling leaves and distant calls of wildlife. It’s as if the forest is sharing its secrets with us. Let’s keep going and see what other wonders this trail has in store for us. Look at us, guys! We’re surrounded by an abundance of greenery as we tread this hidden trail. The air is so fresh, and every step we take brings us deeper into the serene embrace of nature. Embracing the Horizon Description Wow, look at this, guys! We’ve made it to the top, and just take in that view – endless rolling green hills under a sky so vast, it’s breathtaking. Every step of our climb was worth this moment. It feels like we can touch the sky! Let’s take a moment to appreciate this, to breathe in the fresh air, and to realize how far we’ve come. This is what adventure feels like, isn’t it? Wow, look at this, guys! We’ve made it to the top, and just take in that view – endless rolling green hills under a sky so vast, it’s breathtaking. Every step of our climb was worth this moment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Distributed algorithms to System architecture</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2021/09/11/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Distributed algorithms to System architecture" /><published>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2021/09/11/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2021/09/11/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2021.9.11.blog.cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size " style="text-align: center;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Using Distributed algorithms to System architecture</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size " style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Using Distributed algorithms to System architecture</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size ">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
          <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        11 September 2021
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/pebojote" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            09/11/2021
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/pebojote" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <p>In my earlier article, I discussed the abstraction layer, specifically interoperability. We know that an interoperable object can communicate with other system components. Today, however, I'm going to talk to you about distributed algorithms and system architecture. Isn't it true that computers run algorithms? We give the computer the problem, and it uses an algorithm in a silicon-based processor to solve it.</p>
    <p>But what if the problem is given by the computers? What are our options for resolving the issue? What about the executable code? Where do we get it? Computers, of course, can present us with a problem, which we can then solve using an algorithm (thinking) in our heads. The human brain, like the computer, has a silicon-based processor. A distributed algorithm (or distributed thinking) is when the brain of a human and the silicon-based processor of a computer work together to produce an overall result.</p>
    <p>Distributed thinking is possible because it can take advantage of multiple people's ideas running in parallel. It runs in parallel because different people can collaborate to achieve a common goal. Human-based computation is the term for this. The computer distributes a small unit of work to many people in human-based computation (or HBC), which is also known as microwork, to produce an overall result. If no efficient algorithm has yet been created in the computer for microwork, the computer can use the thinking of different people.</p>
    <p>A computer can divide a large piece of work into small units and distribute them across the internet to a large number of people. Microwork is used in Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT), InnoCentive, and Internet Eyes, among other places. In AMT, it can distribute random work. I'm not going to discuss those jobs because they're completely random. InnoCentive, on the other hand, allows a company to ask you a specific question to solve a problem, and if you answer it correctly, they will pay you $50. In Internet Eyes, you can watch CCTV cameras and alert shop owners if there is a potential theft, and they will pay you for it.</p>
    <p>However, a computer that assigns a small unit of work to various people is limited because it can slow down the work if a specific person's thinking is inefficient, resulting in a poor overall result. We must extend it in order to avoid it. Rather than assigning work solely to humans, we can assign it to both humans and computers. It means that a computer can assign tasks to both humans and machines (CH or CC). This relationship of HC, CH, HH, CC, and other components can form a system, and we must understand it. And by using a language, we can comprehend their relationship.</p>
    <p>This is where the system architecture enters the picture. System architecture entails developing an architecture description language (ADL) to describe the relationships between components so that people (developers and stakeholders) can comprehend the system we're building. There are many different types of ADL, but we will use the United Modelling Language (or UML), which is the best. The structure diagram and the behavior diagram are two diagrams used in UML to understand the relationship between components in a system.</p>
    <p>For example, we can show the developers the structure diagrams (used to create a technical architecture) to help them understand our system, because technical architecture focuses more on the structure of the software/system. Another is we can show the stakeholder the behavior diagram (used to create an application architecture), because application architecture focuses more on the behavior (or functionality) of the software/system. Remember that stakeholders value functionality over structure, because no matter how well-structured your software is, if the functionality fails to meet their needs, it is effectively useless to them. There are open-source tools available to assist you in creating this diagram using UML tools.</p>
    <p>We now talked about technical and application architecture. When discussing technical architecture, always remember to consider non-functional requirements. When discussing application architecture, always keep functional requirements in mind. Now I'd like to talk about functional requirements for a moment. The subject of functional requirements is the functionality of software/system. The implementation of functionality can vary depending on the goal of your stakeholder. So I'm not going to go into any more detail.</p>
    <p>Let us now discuss non-functional requirements. Non-functional requirements concern the structure. Consider the differences between monolithic architecture and microservice structure/architecture. If you're new to system architecture, monolithic architecture is a good place to start because it's easier to build but more difficult to manage.</p>
    <p>In monolithic architecture, all of your components have strong coupling, which means that if you change one, it will have a significant impact on another, potentially causing an imbalance in their relationship. To put it another way, if you change one component, you'll have to change all of the others to rebalance their relationship. Consider a game of jenga. When one piece at the bottom is removed, it has an impact on all of the pieces above it. Consider what would happen if you removed that one piece at the bottom by accident. Naturally, all of the pieces above it will fall. That minor blunder could turn into a major blunder. As a result, a microservice architecture is required.</p>
    <p>You can avoid that small mistake that can turn into a big mistake with microservice architecture. Microservice architecture, on the other hand, is difficult to build but easy to manage, whereas monolithic architecture is easier to build but difficult to manage. All of your components in a microservice architecture have weak coupling, which means that if you change one, it will only have a minor impact on the others.</p>
    <p>Meaning, if you change one component, it will affect some but not all of the others. This component (or service) is also small (or micro) and manageable. Making an orchestration, on the other hand, is context-dependent. In orchestration, however, design patterns are common. Because we all use the same design patterns. The pattern of relationships and interactions among components in orchestration is common.</p>
    <p>However, non-functional requirements may cause each component to differ from the others. Is it necessary for one component to be durable while the other requires flexibility? These non-functional requirements can be used to describe the component's purpose. Information architecture includes describing components, which we will discuss next in my blog.</p>
    <h3>Summary</h3>
    <hr />
    <p>The subject of functional requirements is the functionality of software/system. The implementation of functionality can vary depending on the goal of your stakeholder. Non-functional requirements concern the software/structure. Consider the differences between monolithic architecture and microservice architecture. Microservice architecture is difficult to build but easy to manage. </p>
    <p>All of your components in a microservice architecture have weak coupling, which means that if you change one, it will only have a minor impact on the others. This component (or service) is also small (or micro) and manageable. However, non-functional requirements may cause each component to differ from the others. Is it necessary for one component to be durable while the other requires flexibility? These non-functional requirements can be used to describe the component's purpose</p>
</div>
<hr />
<div class="desktop__size ">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/09/11/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    &nbsp;
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/09/11/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my earlier article, I discussed the abstraction layer, specifically interoperability. We know that an interoperable object can communicate with other system components. Today, however, I'm going to talk to you about distributed algorithms and system architecture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is it possible to use an algorithm in a system (or humans)?</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2021/09/01/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is it possible to use an algorithm in a system (or humans)?" /><published>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2021/09/01/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2021/09/01/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2021.9.1.blog.cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size " style="text-align: center;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Is it possible to use an algorithm in a system (or humans)?</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size " style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Is it possible to use an algorithm in a system (or humans)?</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size ">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
          <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        01 September 2021
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/pebojote" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            09/01/2021
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/pebojote" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <p>
        An emotional attachment to a piece of software is a natural part of the human and computer systems. That's right, their operating systems are in sync. If there are no water purification facilities, raw water collection points, or drainage basins in a water supply system, there will be no water storage, such as water towers. I'm not going to go over every component of the water supply system. I'm simply stating that some components of the water supply system are dependent on others.
    </p>
    <p>
        If you live in a city, you can easily imagine this scenario. This has something to do with the abstraction layer. Between water towers and raw water collection points known as water purification facilities, there is an abstraction layer in a water supply system. Of course, we don't want to drink water that hasn't been purified yet. Anyway, I'm not going to get into hydrologic science right now. But all I'm saying is that between the two parts of the system, there's an abstraction layer that allows them to communicate.
    </p>
    <p>
        Interoperability is the term for this. The abstraction layer is also interoperable because it can communicate with both of these components of the system. It means that the abstraction layer is easily understood by those two parts of the system. As a result, the abstraction layer can bring disparate parts together, and that is the only way to refer to something as a system. In addition, the abstraction layer can be used to make different systems work together. Syntactic interoperability is the term for this. Always keep in mind that there are different workers (organization) for each component. This abstraction layer also enables different organizations to collaborate with one another for mutual benefit. Cross-domain interoperability is the term for this.
    </p>
    <p>
        Cross-domain interoperability is important because it can have a negative impact on both organizations if they can't work together. There is, of course, a problem if you are designing a water supply system and do not allow the fire department to use fire hydrants in your pipe network. This is self-evident and requires no further explanation. However, in terms of the software industry, the water supply system is a close standard organization, while the fire department has an open standard. The open standard is both syntactic and cross-domain interoperable in this case, whereas the closed standard is only syntactic interoperable.
    </p>
    <p>
        It's possible that the organization's close standard was established because there wasn't one before, and they were the first to do so, or because of monopoly for market dominance. There is no collaboration between different organizations in close standards, but there is collaboration between different systems within the close standard organization. The issue with strict standards, however, is the support group. The support group is so small, by close standards, that you can count them on one hand. The support group for open standards, on the other hand, is much larger. There could be millions, if not billions, of people who are members. So, let us discuss open standards.
    </p>
    <p>
        The support group for open standards is so large that it may include not only the software industry, but also the government and other industries such as healthcare, transportation, education, and so on, and each industry has representatives. The new common protocol can be discussed or even debated by each representative. This new protocol is part of a larger document that promotes common standards. The public was given access to this common document, which has since become an open standard. Because the open standards support group is so large, the open standards have a higher value than closed standards. The network effect is the term for this phenomenon. In open standards, different organizations use the same exchange formats (such as XML or JSON) and protocols (like HTTP or WS).
    </p>
    <p>
        It's possible that an organization's inability to collaborate with other organizations is due to the lack of an open standard. They are instead using a closed standard. Close standards also have financial ramifications for the company. If a product is not interoperable, for example, it may result in a monopoly. Furthermore, monopoly can lead to abuses such as exclusive dealing, in which a new organization entering the market must adjust their system to the monopolist's system. This isn't interoperability; it's compatibility. One example is Apple's removal of the JVM, which forces you to develop iOS apps using their proprietary standards. There will be no need for collaboration because all you have to do is adjust your system to meet their requirements. Apple, on the other hand, changed their mind three weeks after the OpenJDK project was released.
    </p>
    <p>
        Some monopoly abuses are illegal in most countries and may result in the company's dissolution. Breaking up a monopolist means dividing it into smaller organizational entities that are now owned by different people. A monopoly, on the other hand, isn't always a bad thing. It's only a problem if the abuses are widespread among monopolists. The government has the power to easily circumvent the market, so imposing a breakup is not out of the question. The government, on the other hand, supports open standards because they allow new entrants into the market to adjust their systems based on the decisions of multiple organizations rather than just one. This is beneficial because we value the benefits of a large number of people.
    </p>
    <p>
        Now we'll talk about cross-origin interoperability and syntactic interoperability. Another type of interoperability is what we call an abstraction layer that connects different systems, the language interoperability. The Java programming language is a good example of language interoperability. Because of the Java Virtual Machine (JVM), Java can be used on a variety of systems. However, because different organizations use different programming languages, it is not cross-origin interoperable, but it is syntactically interoperable. As a result, Java is getting closer to the close standard. However, due to OpenJDK, this may not be the case.
    </p>
    <p>
        Because different organizations are working together to create a common protocol, OpenJDK is getting closer to the open standard. However, due to lock-in, OpenJDK may suffer from syntactic interoperability. It means that in the end, you'll be forced to use Oracle JDK. However, we see the problem with using the programming language as an abstraction layer. Another abstraction layer that should be used is referred to as an algorithm. You might be surprised to learn that algorithms are used not only in programming languages, but also in systems. We can use them in system design like system architecture, software architecture, and even information architecture, to name a few applications. As a result, I'd like to talk about them on my blog next.
    </p>
    <h3>Summary</h3>
    <hr />
    <p>
        If there are no water purification facilities, raw water collection points, or drainage basins in a water supply system, there will be no water storage, such as water towers. As a result, the abstraction layer can bring disparate parts together, and that is the only way to refer to something as a system. This abstraction layer also enables different organizations to collaborate with one another for mutual benefit. The issue with strict standards is the support group. The support group for open standards, on the other hand, is much larger.
    </p>
    <p>
        Millions, if not billions, of people who are members of an organization could be involved. Open standards have a higher value than closed standards due to the network effect. Different organizations use the same exchange formats in open standards and protocols in closed standards.
    </p>
    <p>
        Expert: It's possible that an organization's inability to collaborate with other organizations is due to the lack of an open standard. Close standards also have financial ramifications for the company. If a product is not interoperable, for example, it may result in a monopoly. Furthermore, monopoly can lead to abuses such as exclusive dealing, in which a new organization entering the market must adjust their system to the monopolist's system.
    </p>
</div>
<hr />
<div class="desktop__size ">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/09/01/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    &nbsp;
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/09/01/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An emotional attachment to a piece of software is a natural part of the human and computer systems. That's right, their operating systems are in sync. If there are no water purification facilities, raw water collection points, or drainage basins in a water supply system, there will be no water storage, such as water towers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design for the benefit of the community</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2021/08/30/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design for the benefit of the community" /><published>2021-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2021/08/30/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2021/08/30/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2021.8.30.blog.cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size " style="text-align: center;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Design for the benefit of their community</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size " style="text-align: justify;word-break: break-all;font-family:sans-serif;word-spacing: 0px;">
    <h2>Design for the benefit of their community</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size ">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
          <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        30 August 2021
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @workpebojot</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/workpebojot" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @workpebojot on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            08/30/2021
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/workpebojot?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @workpebojot</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/workpebojot" aria-label="Follow @workpebojot on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <p>
        We all know that design is a specification for the creation of objects. And that it is the designer who creates the specifications. There are landscape designers, industrial designers, furniture designers, and other types of designers. However, I'd like to discuss interaction designers. Interaction design (or IxD) is a technique used by an interaction designer. IxD is a technique for creating interactive objects. It could be a physical object like a hammer or a digital object like a computer.
    </p>
    <p>
        Now we'd like to concentrate on computers. When we talk about interactive design on computers, we're really talking about how humans (users) interact with computers. Because the computer is an interactive object, it is a human who interacts with it. The human is the one who gives the computer instructions (instruction environment), and the computer is the one who gives the user the result of the instruction (machine environment). It is based on Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) research (or HCI).
    </p>
    <p>
        Human-computer interaction (HCI) is the study of how people interact with computers. However, we will not discuss everything in HCI because this blog is not the appropriate place to learn everything in HCI, but if you are interested, you can conduct a literature review and publish some research papers by going to a school library or Google Scholar. However, rather than publishing a research paper, we will concentrate on software development.
    </p>
    <p>
        I can only give you a few aspects of HCI that you should be familiar with and will use frequently in software development. So, in HCI, there's a method called User-Centered Design (UCD) that you can use. UCD is an anatomy (or framework) that must be used during the development stage in order to produce a usable product. It's similar to a cheat sheet, a piece of paper that you must pass to each person in the classroom who sits next to you. They must understand that their grade is for their mom, and that the grade is critical in making their mother proud. You should not, of course, cheat.
    </p>
    <p>
        You can imagine the house's designer. Of course, before the framework can be built, the researchers must first gather important information about the user. This will allow us to learn more about the user, pass that information on to the designer, begin construction on the house framework, pass the framework to the house supervisor, and then the supervisor instructs the construction workers on how to use the framework. When we compare this framework for building houses to software development, it's similar to the Swing GUI framework in Java or the Bootstrap framework in JavaScript. As new information about the user becomes available, this framework is refined and refined again during acceptance testing. However, participatory design is where the framework is best refined.
    </p>
    <p>
        Participatory design is a technique for fine-tuning the framework. All stakeholders are involved in participatory design. Employees, suppliers, customers, or end users are all involved in participatory design, for example. Of course, if your general team is involved, this approach will be much more effective. Researchers, developers, testers, and others, for example, are all involved. We design alongside them in participatory design to create an appropriate culture and emotions. This is related to placemaking, which is the process of designing a space based on the people who live there. That is, the community is the focal point of placemaking.
    </p>
    <p>
        When we connect placemaking to participatory design, we're saying that stakeholders know more than the rest of the team. Because you can't conduct participatory design if you don't know what problem you're trying to solve if you're just starting to create a software product, some people try to conduct a literature review to extract some problems before conducting participatory design. Participatory design, on the other hand, only allows us to fine-tune the problem we're trying to solve. This will enable us to create an emotional bond between our target user and the solution we're developing.
    </p>
    <h3>Summary</h3>
    <hr />
    <p>
        This blog is based on Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) research (or HCI). HCI is the study of how people interact with computers. In HCI, there's a technique called User-Centered Design that you can use (UCD). UCD is an anatomy (or framework) that must be used in order to produce a user-friendly product. All stakeholders are involved in participatory design - employees, suppliers, customers, or end users - and we design alongside them to create an appropriate culture and emotions.This is related to placemaking, which is the process of designing a space based on the people who live there. Participatory design allows us to fine-tune the problem we're trying to solve so we can create an emotional bond between our target user and the solution we're developing.
    </p>
</div>
<hr />
<div class="desktop__size ">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/08/30/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    &nbsp;
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="workpebojot">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="workpebojot">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2021/08/30/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all know that design is a specification for the creation of objects. And that it is the designer who creates the specifications. There are landscape designers, industrial designers, furniture designers, and other types of designers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern approach and practice for CI and CD</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2021/08/28/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern approach and practice for CI and CD" /><published>2021-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2021/08/28/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2021/08/28/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2021.8.28.blog.cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" alt="cover" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size" style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <h2>Modern approach and practice for CI and CD</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size" style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <h2>Modern approach and practice for CI and CD</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
        <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
    </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        28 August 2021
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/pebojote" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
 </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            08/28/2021
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/pebojote" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <p>
        Defects are common in software development, as we all know. When you come across it, you can be sure that stakeholders are unhappy with it, and they will ask you how long they should wait for a fix (or changes). You can try to tell them the time, but they are interested in more than just the time. They care about how the changes are delivered. In software development, the product that can change the most quickly in a constrained environment win, while those who are slow to change lose. As a result, mistakes must be discovered early, and changes must be delivered quickly. Change delivery necessitates some practice (practice) and a software engineering approach (approach), so we must employ continuous integration (practice), continuous delivery and continuous deployment (approach).
    </p>
    <p>
         So, first and foremost, I'd like to discuss continuous integration (or CI). It's more of a (practice) than a tool. The tool is designed to aid in practice. Back in the day, we used source code management (SCM) in a source code control system (SCCS). Branching and merging were common in SCM for code review (CR) purposes, similar to what developers do in extreme programming (XP). They review each other's code, that's right. In branching, every branch should go to the CR branch, but the problem is that other branches' changes are too late or too early, so merging to the CR branch produces contradictory results because two changes from two branches collide, and they reject it.
    </p>
    <p>
        As a result, researchers are considering new practices to solve the problem, one of which is to use continuous integration (CI). CI is a practice similar to what we do in XP, but it does not involve branching or merging. Instead, there is only one mainline, and you must commit to that mainline every day. This is referred to as a daily build. Mistakes are discovered early in a daily build, and if the build fails, it can be quickly identified, and the changes can then be delivered.
    </p>
    <p>
        So, what should we do if the build goes well? We must, of course, test in the build. Testing in the build is more than just that. Because CI necessitates the use of a test suite. The term test suite refers to a collection of test cases (with a test case ID). This means that for each defect-fix commit (with an issue ID on the issue board), that defect-fix commit will be tracked separately using a traceability matrix. And if it passes, we generate executables, which we then deploy. Even if you used continuous integration back then, some people did manual building, manual testing, and manual deployment, which made CI slower. As a result, we'll need a strategy for dealing with automation. Here's where the CI/CD comes in handy.
    </p>
    <p>
       So, now I'd like to discuss continuous delivery (CD). Remember that when we use CD, we're using an (approach) rather than a tool like Jenkins or GoCD. Only those approaches will benefit from the tool, which will automate some tasks such as building, testing, and deploying. When you use a Kanban system, you can make better use of CDs (the pipeline). As an example, consider a pipeline. Each pipeline has different stages, as we all know. As an example, 
    </p>
    <p>
        Stage 1: Research (manual) <br />
        Stage 2: Architecture (software or system) and Design (manual) <br />
        Stage 3: Development (manual or automated) <br />
        Stage 4: Testing (manual or automated) <br />
        Stage 5: Deployment (automated) <br />
        Stage 6: Monitoring <br />
    </p>
    <p>
        Stages 3 to 5 can be automated, but not completely, because some sub-stages are still required because each stage can be broken down even further. As an example,
    </p>
    <p>
        Stage 3: Development <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.1 code commit (manual) <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.2 code review (automated or manual) <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.2.1 check code style/standard <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.2.2 rearrange code <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.2.3 check copyright <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.2.4 etc. <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.3 version control system (automated) <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.4 automation server (Jenkins or GoCD) <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3.4.1 build (automated) <br />
        Stage 4: Testing <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 4.1 unit test (automated) <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 4.2 acceptance test (manual or automated) <br />
        &nbsp; &nbsp; 4.3 release (automated) <br />
        Stage 5: Deployment (automated)
    </p>
    <p>
        Note that code review in the IDE can be automated, but not in text/code editors such as VS Code or Notepad++. It's also worth noting that we have "manual or automated" on the same stage. This implies that the stage can be further subdivided. For example, in acceptance testing, there is regression testing (automated), sanity testing (manual) and more. In stage 4.3, the release, they can be executables like jar files (Java) or static files (JavaScript). It indicates that the files are ready for deployment, and that the files will be deployed using a CD automatically. Smaller items flow through the pipeline faster than larger items. This is to avoid making major mistakes. If the items are small, the mistakes are small, and fixing them if they occur is easy.
    </p>
    <p>
        Because a successful build can still fail in production due to software incompatibility, some developers use feature toggle to ensure that if one feature fails in production, we can turn it off. The tasks in the pipeline are synchronous, and at each stage, people with varying skills may be involved. Researchers are involved in the first stage. They could be data scientists, such as data miners, machine learning scientists, or big data analysts, among other things. Software architects, system architects, information architects, UX designers, and even psychologists are involved in the second stage.
    </p>
    <p>
        It's because they need to create documentation (or specification) so that the developers can put it into practice. Isn't this documentation familiar to us? We know this because when we use community dependencies (such as open-source libraries), we read the documentation. However, in commercial dependency, some documentation is private and only available within the enterprise. As a result, in my next blog, I'd like to discuss stage 2, the architecture and design.
    </p>
    <h3>Summary</h3>
    <hr />
    <p>
        In software development, the product that can change the most quickly in a constrained environment win, while those who are slow to change lose. We must employ continuous integration (practice), continuous delivery and continuous deployment (approach). CI is a practice similar to what we do in XP, but it does not involve branching or merging. In stage 4.3, the release, they can be executables like jar files (Java) or static files (JavaScript). It indicates that the files are ready for deployment, and will be deployed using a CD automatically.
    </p>
  </div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2022/08/28/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2022/08/28/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Defects are common in software development, as we all know. When you come across it, you can be sure that stakeholders are unhappy with it, and they will ask you how long they should wait for a fix (or changes).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Software Defects Management for Mistake</title><link href="http://localhost:3000/2021/08/25/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software Defects Management for Mistake" /><published>2021-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:3000/2021/08/25/blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/2021/08/25/blog/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2021.8.25.blog.cover.png" class="rounded img-fluid" alt="cover" /></p>

<div class="desktop__size" style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <h2>Software Defects Management for Mistake</h2>
</div>
<div class="mobile__size" style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <h2>Software Defects Management for Mistake</h2>
</div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
    <div class="align-self-center">
        <small class="text-muted">
        <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
        </small>
    </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        By Edison Pebojot
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        25 August 2021
      </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a>
        <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
      </div>
      &nbsp;
      <div class="align-self-center">
        <a class="github-button" href="https://github.com/pebojote" data-color-scheme="no-preference: light; light: light; dark: light;" data-size="large" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
      </div>
    </div>
 </div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <small class="text-muted">
                <img src="/assets/images/2.webp" width="30" height="30" class="img-fluid rounded-circle" alt="Edison Pebojot" />
            </small>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            By Edison Pebojot
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center flex-grow-1">
            08/25/2021
        </div>
    </div>
    <p></p>
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/pebojote?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-follow-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false">Follow @pebojote</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        &nbsp;
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a class="github-button align-self-center" href="https://github.com/pebojote" aria-label="Follow @pebojote on GitHub">Follow</a>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: justify;word-break: keep-all;font-family:sans-serif;">
    <p>
        So, in my previous blog, I discussed debt. Other types of debt exist, such as architecture debt, infrastructure debt, and so on, but I'd like to focus on technical debt today because it is the most common type of debt in the software industry. As a result, one of the most common topics discussed by experienced programmers in the software industry is technical debt. So, when we talk about technical debt, we're actually talking about software defects. Because the term bug can refer to insects, some people prefer to refer to it as a defect, because a defect is the result of a mistake. This is called Mistake metamorphism.
    </p>
    <p>
        In mistake metamorphism, when we change some parts of the source code, we may need to change other parts of the source code as well in order for the software to function properly. Unfortunately, some of us would rather not change certain other parts (or components) for various reasons (maybe because it was hard to change). This is a mistake. And this mistake continues to flow through the pipeline (or Kanban board). That mistake slowly transforms into something dark as it travels through the pipeline. It's so dark that it's now considered a defect in the pipeline's final stage (deployment). And that defect can result in software that isn't up to par. It means that some of it is functional, but not all of it is. For example, clicking the button is working, but clicking the anchor is not.
    </p>
    <p>
        When some parts of a programme work before but not after a change, this is referred to as software regression (defect). Some defects, however, are unintentional. For example, just because you change some parts of the source code and leave the rest alone to make the software work perfectly does not mean there isn't a defect. It could be due to incompatibilities that cause the software to perform poorly. Some parts (components) of your software, for example, may not work in the runtime environment. This is due to the execution model's inability to comprehend your source code. It's possible that the execution model from that runtime entails using "if statement" with parenthesis instead.
    </p>
    <p>
        This type of incompatibility is called Software incompatibility. It's also possible that the runtime environment has been updated and no longer supports the programming language features you're using (or vice versa). And it's here that forward and backward compatibility is established. Forward compatibility is used when your software needs to work flawlessly with a new version of the runtime environment. Backward compatibility is available for older versions of the runtime environment. Because your system is still young and mistakes are common, you're more likely to encounter intentional defects in greenfield projects.
    </p>
    <p>
        Defect triage, on the other hand, can be used to manage defects. Some tools, such as Github or Trello, refer to this as bug triage, but this is incorrect. If you rely on these tools excessively, you may be justified in using the term bug triage during working hours, and you may disagree with me. Using the word defect, on the other hand, is transparent because it indicates that you made a mistake, which you should not hide from the public.
    </p>
    <p>
        In any case, the most common method of defect triage is through the use of a tool and a casual meeting. To avoid infobesity, the tool includes a defect triage board (board), four columns (open, high priority, low priority, closed), and a WiP limit for each column. The developer who made the mistake in the version control system should speak with the tester during the casual meeting. Some prefer to speak with stakeholders and product owners because they are more familiar with the scope of the technical debt's impact and may be able to offer useful solutions. Some people prefer to use an issue board instead of talking to stakeholders and product owners. An issue board is preferable because it allows more people to discuss the problem than just the developer and tester.
    </p>
    <p>
        Rather than adding a defect to the issue board, some developers prefer to avoid mistakes right away. However, some errors are unintentional, such as software incompatibility. But mistakes can also be reduced to a bare minimum. As a result, we must prioritise and estimate the issue. You need to know the issue's value and size in order to prioritise and estimate it. The output of resolving the problem must be useful to the user, and the impact should be minimal. It should be kept to a minimum because a large impact means a large mistake. And, no matter how significant the impact, most users will not value what you fix if the issue is not valuable. This can lead to a waste of time.
    </p>
    <p>
        In addition to size and value, people use velocity (for scrum) and time (for kanban). In fact, in software development, velocity and time are critical because they are used to communicate with stakeholders. The standard deviation formula is used to calculate the mean of the total number of story points in four sprints over the course of a month. However, because the velocity has no units like tasks per minute, there are trust issues between the team and the stakeholders. As a result, some people attempt to convert velocity to time. For instance, 30 points equals 6 days, 60 points equals 12 days, and so on. T-shirt sizing and the cone of uncertainty are also used by some people to communicate with stakeholders, but this is beyond the scope of this blog.
    </p>
    <p>
        As a result, some people prefer to use time (in kanban). You use time in kanban to communicate with stakeholders about how long they should expect their product to arrive. Lead time, cycle time, and actionable agile metrics (ACM) are used to calculate time. I won't go into detail because it's much better if you investigate it for yourself to gain a better understanding. All of this talk about velocity and time, on the other hand, is a way of communicating to stakeholders how long it will take to fix the defect. You'll need a way to explain to stakeholders how long they should wait for the fix, especially if the defect is valuable.
    </p>
    <h3>Summary</h3>
    <hr />
    <p>
        Technical debt is the most common type of debt in the software industry. Technical debt refers to software defects, which can be caused by mistake and incompatibilities. Some people prefer to refer to it as a defect, because a defect is the result of a mistake. In mistake metamorphism, when we change some parts of the source code, we may need to change other parts too. And this mistake slowly transforms into something dark as it travels through the pipeline.
    </p>
    <p>
        It's so dark that it's now considered a defect in the pipeline's final stage (deployment) And that defect can result in software that isn't up to par. Some tools, such as Github or Trello, refer to bug triage as bug triage, but this is incorrect. Using the word defect, on the other hand, is transparent because it indicates that you made a mistake, which you should not hide from the public. If you rely on these tools excessively, you may be justified in using the term bug trage during working hours, and you may disagree with me.
    </p>
    <p>
        The most common method of defect triage is through the use of a tool and a casual meeting. Some people prefer to use an issue board instead of talking to stakeholders and product owners. The output of resolving the problem must be useful to the user, and the impact should be minimal. This is because it should be kept to a minimum because a large impact means a large mistake. Some people prefer to use time (in kanban) to communicate with stakeholders about how long they should expect their product to arrive.
    </p>
    <p>
        Lead time, cycle time, and actionable agile metrics (ACM) are used to calculate time. Time is a way of communicating to stakeholders how long it will take to fix a defect, especially if the defect is critical. It's much better if you investigate it for yourself to gain a better understanding.
    </p>
  </div>
<hr />

<div class="desktop__size">
  <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2022/08/25/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="large"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
    </div>
    <div class="align-self-center">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button" data-size="large" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a>
      <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="mobile__size">
    <div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-start">
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <a href="https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" class="twitter-share-button align-self-center" data-show-screen-name="false" data-show-count="false" data-via="pebojote">Tweet</a><script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
        </div>
        <div class="align-self-center">
            <div class="fb-share-button align-self-center" style="vertical-align: super;top:-2px" data-href="https://www.pebojot.com/2022/08/25/blog/" data-layout="button" data-size="small"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdevelopers.facebook.com%2Fdocs%2Fplugins%2F&amp;src=sdkpreparse" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">Share</a></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pebojot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, in my previous blog, I discussed debt. Other types of debt exist, such as architecture debt, infrastructure debt, and so on, but I'd like to focus on technical debt today because it is the most common type of debt in the software industry.]]></summary></entry></feed>